<!-- ============= Interface ============================== -->
	
 <!-- ============= Menubar  ============-->
	<sect2 id="menubar">
   		<title>Menubar</title>
   		<para>
   		At the top of the <application>Xiphos</application> main window is the menubar. 
   		Almost all of the functions are available by activating the appropriate 
   		menu item. The functions have been grouped according to their type. For 
   		example, the file operations have been grouped into 
   		the <guisubmenu>File</guisubmenu> menu.
   		</para>
	        <figure id="menubar_figure">
			<title>Menubar</title>
	  		<screenshot> 
			  <mediaobject> 
			    <imageobject><imagedata
				fileref="figures/interface_menubar.png" format="PNG" /> 
			    </imageobject>
	    		<!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
          		<!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      			<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_menubar.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
		    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>&appname; menubar</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
		      	</screenshot>
	    	</figure>
	</sect2>
	
<!-- ============= Toolbars  ============-->
	<sect2 id="toolbars">
   		<title>Toolbars</title>
   		<para>
	    	The function of the Toolbar is to provide control over the Bible and Commentary Panes.
		Activation of the Toolbar option is done by moving the mouse cursor over the 
		desired toolbar button and selecting it. A tooltip will appear if the mouse cursor 
		is held stationary over a toolbar button, describing the function of the button. 
    	</para>
		<figure id="toolbar_figure">
			<title>ToolBar</title>
			<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject>
		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_toolbar.png" format="PNG"/> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_toolbar.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>The Toolbar</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	</screenshot>
		</figure>	
		<para>
		The <interface>Toolbar</interface> consists of the following functions:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
				History View Toggle and drop-down menu
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
				Bible Book Selector
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
				Bible Chapter Selector
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
				Bible Verse Selector
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
				Bible Passage Summary
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
		<sect3>
			<title>History Forward/Backward Selector</title>
			<para>
			Switches between current and previous passage selections.
			</para>
		</sect3>
			
		<sect3 id="xiphos-toolbar-book">
			<title>Bible Book Selector</title>
			<para>		
			Selects the Biblical book to be displayed in the <interface>Bible Text Pane</interface> and 
			<interface>Commentary Pane</interface>. Changes take immediate effect.
			</para>
		</sect3>
			
		<sect3 id="xiphos-toolbar-chapter">
			<title>Bible Chapter Selector</title>
			<para>
			Selects the Biblical chapter of current book to be displayed in the <interface>Bible Text Pane</interface> and 
			<interface>Commentary Pane</interface>. Changes take immediate effect.
			</para>
		</sect3>
			
		<sect3 id="xiphos-toolbar-verse">
			<title>Bible Verse Selector</title>
			<para>
			Selects the Biblical verse of current chapter to be displayed in the <interface>Bible Text Pane</interface> and 
			<interface>Commentary Pane</interface>. Changes take immediate effect.
			</para>
		</sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-toolbar-summary">
			<title>Bible Passage Summary</title>
			<para>
			Allows manual editing of passages which are displayed in the <interface>Bible Text Pane</interface> and 
			<interface>Commentary Pane</interface>. Changes take effect once Enter is typed.
			</para>
			<warning>
				<para>
				Ensure that edited book,chapter and verse naming is correct, otherwise the wrong or no information
				will be displayed.
				</para>
			</warning>
		</sect3>
	</sect2>
   
<!-- ============= Sidebar  ============-->  
	<sect2 id="xiphos-sidebar">
   	 	<title>The Sidebar</title>
		<figure id="sidebar_figure">
			<title>Sidebar</title>
	  		<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject>
		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_sidepane.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_sidepane.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>The Sidebar</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	   </screenshot>

	    	</figure>
		<para>
	     	On the left hand side of <application>Xiphos</application> there is the Sidebar. Here the user can switch between the different Sword modules,
	     	view bookmarks, do simple searches and view verse lists. In the Modules listing, a module may be chosen for viewing in the current tab of the
	     	main window by clicking it.  Using the context (right-click) menu, other options are to open a new tab using the module, open a separate
	     	(i.e. detached) window, or to view the "About" information for the module.
		</para>
		<para>
		To switch between all Sidebar functions, buttons have been placed at the top of the Sidebar.
		</para>
		<figure id="shortcut_figure">
			<title>Sidebar Shortcuts</title>
	  		<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject>
		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_shortcut.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_shortcut.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>Sidebar shortcuts</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
			</screenshot>
	    	</figure>
	</sect2>
<!-- ============= Bible Text Pane  ============--> 
	<sect2 id="xiphos-bible">
   		<title>The Bible Text Pane</title>
  		<figure id="textpane_figure">
			<title>The Bible Textpane</title>
	  		<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject>
		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_biblepane.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_biblepane.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>The Bible textpane</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
			</screenshot>
	    	</figure>
		<para>
		Positioned to the right of the Shortcut bar is the Bible text pane. All translations are displayed here.  When starting
		<application>Xiphos</application>, the translation last used in the leftmost tab will be displayed.
		</para>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-bible-open">
			<title>Opening A Specific Bible Translation</title>
			<para>
			In order to change the current Bible translation to another of your choice:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					right-click in the <interface>Bible Text Pane</interface>. In the popup menu choose
					<menuchoice><guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Open Module</guimenuitem></menuchoice>
					and select your specific translation that you want to view.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					under the <guibutton>Modules</guibutton> option in the <interface>Sidebar</interface>, choose <menuchoice>
					<guimenuitem>Biblical Texts</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>language choice</guimenuitem></menuchoice>
					and select your specific translation. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-bible-parallel">
			<title>Using the Parallel View Mode</title>
			<para>
			A nice function in <application>Xiphos</application> is the ability to view your specified bible text in several
			parallel translations of your choice.  The Parallel View mode can be accessed by selecting <guimenuitem>Parallel
			View</guimenuitem> just below the <interface>Bible Text Pane</interface>, next to the <guimenuitem>Standard
			View</guimenuitem> tab.
			</para>
			<para>
			You must choose which modules to display in parallel with the <guibutton>Preferences</guibutton> dialog found under
			the <guimenuitem>Edit</guimenuitem> menu.  In the dialog, choose Modules, then Parallel.  You can add or subtract
			from the list of modules that will be shown in the parallel view.  The toolbar gives you a selector tool to erase
			the list, delete a module from the list, and add modules to the list.
			</para>
			<para>
			The <guimenuitem>Parallel View</guimenuitem> shows just one verse at a time.  You can change the verse by selecting
			another verse, chapter, or book at the toolbar. Also note that modules that are Old Testament or New Testament only
			(e.g. Westminster Leningrad Codex, Byzantine Majority Text) will not be able to display books that they don't have.
			</para>
		<figure id="parallel_figure">
			<title>Bible textpane - parallel view</title>
	  		<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata fileref="figures/interface_parallel.png" format="PNG" />
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_parallel.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>Bible textpane - parallel view</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
		      	</screenshot>
	    	</figure>
			<para>
			Additionally, a separate Parallel View window can be selected from the right click menu with <guimenuitem>Detach/Attach</guimenuitem>.
			Your Bible pane will return to its normal single text view, and the new Parallel View window will show the complete
			chapter, showing the same translations.
			</para>
		<figure id="parallel_figure_separate">
			<title>Parallel View - separate window</title>
	  		<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata fileref="figures/interface_parallel-separate.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_parallel-separate.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>Parallel View - separate window</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
		      	</screenshot>
		</figure>
		</sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-bible-open-separate">
			<title>Opening A Separate Bible Translation</title>
			<para>
			In order to view a Bible translation separate from the <application>Xiphos</application> main window interface, under the
			<guibutton>Modules</guibutton> option in the <interface>Sidebar</interface>, choose <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Biblical
			Texts</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>language choice</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.  Then right-click on a translation and choose
			<guimenuitem>Open in dialog</guimenuitem>. The module will open in a separate, detached window of its own.
			</para>
			<para>
			Detached Bible and commentary windows have a synchronization button in the upper-left position beside the navigation bar.  When this
			button is depressed, the main window Bible and commentary will synchronize with detached Bible and commentary windows.  The
			synchronization goes both ways: Any detached window will synchronize navigation with all other detached Bibles and commentaries plus the
			main window, and the main window will drive all detached Bibles and commentaries whose synchronization button is depressed.
			</para>
		</sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-bible-about">
			<title>Finding Out About The Current Translation</title>
			<para>
			To find out about the Bible translation currently being displayed:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					right-click in the <interface>Bible Text pane</interface>. In the popup menu choose
					<guimenuitem>About </guimenuitem> module name.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					Under the <guibutton>Modules</guibutton> option in the <interface>Sidebar</interface>,choose <menuchoice>
					<guimenuitem>Biblical Texts</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>language choice</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
					Then right-click on a translation and choose the <guimenuitem>About</guimenuitem>
					option.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-bible-options">
			<title>Module Options</title>
			<para>
			Most Bible translations have additional options which the user can select.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					Words Of Christ In Red
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					Strong's Numbers
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					Morphological Tags
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>	
					<para>
					Footnotes
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>	
					<para>
					Scripture Cross-Reference
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>	
					<para>
					Headings
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>	
					<para>
					Image Content
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<note>
				<para>
				Translations in other languages such as Greek or Hebrew have specific options which deal only with the specific language.
				</para>
			</note>
			<para>
				In order to access these options:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					right-click in the <interface>Bible Text pane</interface>. In the popup menu (example shown), choose
					<guibutton>Module Options</guibutton> and select the specific option.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<figure id="module_options">
				<title>Module Options</title>
		  		<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata fileref="figures/interface_biblepane-options.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_biblepane-options.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>Module Options</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
			      	</screenshot>
		    	</figure>
		</sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-view-options">
			<title>View Options</title>
			<para>
			There are several additional modes that can be selected from the menubar's <guimenuitem>View</guimenuitem> pulldown.
			</para>
			<figure id="view_options">
				<title>View Options</title>
		  		<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata fileref="figures/interface_menubar-view.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_menubar-view.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>View Options</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
			      	</screenshot>

		    	</figure>
			<para>
			The first 4 checkboxes control whether each named subwindow is displayed.  The viewable state of the subwindows is remembered on a
			per-tab basis.  This makes it possible, for example, to have a tab dedicated to a maps module alone (in a dictionary module, having
			alphabetically-listed places), by turning off the display of Bible, Previewer, and Commentary for that tab.
			</para>
			<para>
			The remaining checkboxes control these other display features:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>	
					<para>
					Link Tabs - When more than one tab is open, each one's verse is navigated separately in the disabled
					case.  If tab linking is enabled, then all tabs navigate together, keeping all translations on the
					same verse.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>	
					<para>
					Read Aloud - If you enable this, then <application>Xiphos</application> will funnel all selected verses
					through the <application>festival</application> text-to-speech system.  <application>Festival</application> is
					a widely-available TTS, often installed by default in Linux distributions.
					</para>
					<para>
					Also, mouse-selected text may be read aloud from Bibles, commentaries, and general books, using the
					right-click menu, regardless of whether Read Aloud is selected.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				<listitem>	
					<para>
					Show Verse Numbers - Normally enabled, this toggle can be disabled to prevent display of verse
					numbers within the text.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>	
					<para>
					Highlight Current Verse - Initially disabled, this toggle replaces mere alternate colorization of
					the current verse with a substitute high-contrast highlight.  The colors used may be selected from
					the Preferences dialog.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-default-css">
			<title>Display Control with CSS</title>
			<para>
			Users familiar with CSS (cascading style sheets) may wish to create the file "default-style.css" in the .xiphos
			directory to contain whatever CSS controls are desired.  Beware, it is very easy to shoot oneself in the foot with CSS, and this
			will affect all modules' display.  The facility exists to provide the capability that advanced users may wish.
			</para>
		</sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-user-annotation">
			<title>User Annotation</title>
			<para>
			Many users wish to make personal annotations on individual verses, without the need to put a full "personal
			commentary" module to use.  <application>Xiphos</application> provides this in the right-click context menu in the
			Bible pane.  This brings up a dialog showing the current verse reference and offering a text box into which to enter
			a brief personal note.  Once the user closes the dialog with "Annotate Verse," the verse will be displayed in
			reverse-highlight (default, blue on yellow) and a marker <guibutton>*u</guibutton> will be inserted at the verse's
			beginning.  This is metaphorically similar for users who mark verses in paper Bibles with a yellow highlighter and
			write personal notes in the margins.
			</para>
			<para>
			Selecting an already-annotated verse will (in the usual case) bring up the existing content for re-editing.  An
			already-annotated verse can be unmarked; the verse will cease to show in reverse-highlight.
			</para>
			<para>
			If the user deletes the module name from the reference at the top of the dialog, then the annotation will apply to any Bible
			module at the selected verse.  However, in this case, re-selecting the annotated verse will not initialize with the existing
			content, because the dialog is created based on the specific module reference.
			</para>
		</sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-geography-support">
			<title>Geography Support</title>
			<para>
			A connection to browsing BibleMap.org is available by mouse-selecting a place name in any text.  Use the right-click context
			menu to select <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Lookup Selection</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Browse in
			BibleMap.org</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.  A web browser will be brought up to show the selected name's geography via
			BibleMap, which provides Biblical detail overlaid on a Google Maps interface.
			</para>
			<para>
			</para>
		</sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-bible-dictionary">
			<title>Specific Word Meanings</title>
			<para>
			In order to check the meaning of a specific word, double-click on the word you wish to lookup. The word should then highlight itself and the
			explanation should be displayed, if available, in the <interface>Dictionary Pane</interface>. 
			</para>
		</sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-bible-find">
			<title>Finding A Specific Word</title>
			<para>
			To find a specific word within a passage:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					right-click in the <interface>Bible Text Pane</interface>. In the popup menu, choose
					<menuchoice><guisubmenu>Edit</guisubmenu><guimenuitem>Find</guimenuitem></menuchoice>. A dialog will
					appear, which provides text searches. Fill out dialog and click the <guibutton>Find</guibutton> and
					<guibutton>Find Next</guibutton> buttons.  </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</sect3>
	</sect2>
<!-- ============= Previewer	================ -->
	<sect2 id="xiphos-viewer">
		<title>Previewer</title>
		<figure id="viewer_figure">
			<title>PreViewer</title>
	  		<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata fileref="figures/interface_viewer.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_viewer.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>Previewer</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
		      	</screenshot>
		</figure>
		<para>
		The Previewer is where the user sees Strong's numbers, morphological tags, footnotes, and cross-references that the
		<interface>Bible Text Pane</interface> provides.
		</para>
		<para>
		Footnote content is displayed in the Previewer when you hover over the indicator <guibutton>*n</guibutton> in the Bible text;
		it remains visible until your mouse moves over another indicator, Strong's number, etc. Sometimes you may want the text to
		remain anchored until you can move the mouse to the previewer to click on a link or to read large footnotes. To anchor the text so
		that you can scroll it in the Previewer, middle-click the indicator (or hold down the <guibutton>Shift key</guibutton>)
		and move to the Previewer.
		</para>
		<para>
		Cross-reference indicators <guibutton>*x</guibutton> work much the same way.  Clicking the
		indicator will send the set of references to the <guibutton>Verse List</guibutton> in the
		<interface>Sidebar</interface>, where you can click them individually for reading in the Previewer.
                Alternately, a Preferences selector is available, so that cross-reference lists are sent to the
                verse list instead.
		</para>
		<para>
		Any verses shown in reverse-highlight have personal annotation associated with them, and such verses will include
		<guibutton>*u</guibutton> at the beginning of the verse.  Hovering on this marker will show the annotation in the previewer, just as
		for publisher's footnotes.
		</para>
		<para>
		If a devotional has been set via the Preferences dialog, then the day's devotional reference will also appear in the
		previewer, either on program startup or when the user requests it via the <guimenuitem>View</guimenuitem> menu.
		</para>
	</sect2>	
<!-- ============= Commentary Pane  ============--> 
	<sect2 id="xiphos-commentaries">
   		<title>The Commentary Pane</title>
		<figure id="commentary_figure">
			<title>The Commentary Pane</title>
	  		<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata
		fileref="figures/interface_commentarypane.png" format="PNG" />
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/interface_commentarypane.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>Commentary Pane</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
	      		</screenshot>
    		</figure>
		<para>
		The <interface>Commentary pane</interface> is where the commentary modules are displayed. This provides easy
		reading, reference, and access to different commentaries currently installed. The passage viewed by the 
		<interface>Commentary pane</interface> is directly controlled by the current passage viewed in the <interface>Bible
		Text pane</interface>, so in order to change to a different passage commentary, select the desired passage
		on the <interface>Toolbar</interface>.
		</para>
		<para>
		If there are images that are part of a commentary, general book, or dictionary/lexicon, they may be clicked to invoke a
		viewer on that single image, in order to get a better view.  This is particularly useful if image resizing has been enabled
		with the result that images are made very small in the subwindow.
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>
			By changing to passage settings on the <interface>Toolbar</interface>, the contents in the 
			<interface>Bible Text pane</interface> and the <interface>Commentary Pane</interface> will be changed. 	
			</para>
		</note>
		
		<sect3 id="xiphos-commentary-about">
			<title>Finding Out About The Commentary Module</title>
			<para>
			To find out about the commentary currently being displayed:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					right-click in the <interface>Commentary Pane</interface>. In the popup menu choose
					<guimenuitem>About </guimenuitem> module name.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</sect3>

		<sect3 id="xiphos-commentary-headings">
			<title>Commentary Headings.</title>
			<para>
			Many commentaries have additional headings which enable introductory information about the book and chapter currently
			being displayed in the <interface>Bible Text pane</interface>. In order to view them:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					right-click in the <interface>Commentary Pane</interface>. In the popup menu choose
					<guimenuitem>Display Book Heading</guimenuitem> or <guimenuitem>Display Chapter Heading</guimenuitem>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</sect3>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="xiphos-dictionary">
		<title>Dictionary Pane</title>
		<figure id="dict_figure">
			<title>The Dictionary Pane</title>
	  		<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata
		fileref="figures/interface_dictionary.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/image.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>The Dictionary Pane</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
	      		</screenshot>
    		</figure>

		<para>
		The Dictionary Pane's content is driven by its up/down selectors, typing in its navbar text, or double-clicks in the Bible, Commentary, or Book Panes.
		</para>
	</sect2>

	<sect2 id="xiphos-shortcut">
		<title>Keyboard Shortcuts</title>
		<para>
		Several keyboard shortcuts exist in <application>Xiphos</application>, listed below in rough functional groupings.
		</para>
		<para>
		Window selection/opening and navbar selection:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-L</guibutton> focuses and selects the main verse navbar text.  You can then immediately type
					in new verse selection text.  Be aware that, as is the case with most Sword applications,
					<application>Xiphos</application> understands many abbreviations: "G" is adequate to specify Genesis,
					for example, and any book name by itself implies 1:1.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Alt-C</guibutton> brings the Commentary View forward when previously obscured by the Book View.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Alt-G</guibutton> is the opposite of Alt-C, focusing on the general book.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Alt-D</guibutton> focuses on the dictionary navbar text.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-T</guibutton> opens a new tab.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-[1-9]</guibutton> makes the Nth tab current.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>
		Verse navigation and Bible features:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>Ctrl-p/Ctrl-n</guibutton>: Verse previous/next. Also <guibutton>k/j</guibutton>.</para>
				As well, text of the verses before and after the current chapter can be clicked to navigate across chapters.
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>p/n</guibutton>: Chapter previous/next.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>P/N</guibutton>: Book previous/next.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>Shift-F10</guibutton> brings up the context menu for the Bible pane.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>Alt-S</guibutton>: Toggle Strong's display.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>Alt-M</guibutton>: Toggle morphology display.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>Alt-L</guibutton>: Toggle lemma display.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>Alt-R</guibutton>: Toggle "red words of Christ" display.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><guibutton>Alt-T</guibutton>: Toggle transliteration.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>
		Opening special windows:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
		        <listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>F1</guibutton> opens this manual.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>F2</guibutton>: opens the <guibutton>Preferences</guibutton> dialog.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>F3</guibutton>: opens <guibutton>Advanced Search</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-F3</guibutton>: brings forward the simple sidebar search.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>F4</guibutton>: opens the <guibutton>Module Manager</guibutton>.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>F11</guibutton>: opens the current Bible as a separate window.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Alt-A</guibutton> opens an annotation dialog on the current verse.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Alt-B</guibutton> opens a bookmark dialog on the current verse.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-F</guibutton> opens the "Find" dialog.  The subwindow to which it applies depends on which
					of them are visible: The Bible is first preference, then the commentary or general book, then the
					dictionary.  So a tab can be dedicated to just a book, and Ctrl-F will perform "Find" within that pane.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Alt-P</guibutton> detaches/re-attaches the parallel view dialog.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Alt-Z</guibutton> opens editor on the personal commentary named Personal.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>
		Font size control:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-Plus/Ctrl-Minus</guibutton> increases/decreases the base font size.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-0</guibutton> (zero) sets the base font size to zero.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>
		BibleSync:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-Alt-Shift-P</guibutton> puts BibleSync into Personal mode.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-Alt-Shift-S</guibutton> puts BibleSync into Speaker mode.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-Alt-Shift-A</guibutton> puts BibleSync into Audience mode.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-Alt-Shift-O</guibutton> turns off BibleSync.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<guibutton>Ctrl-Alt-Shift-N</guibutton> causes BibleSync to navigate your current main window point
					transiently as a one-shot event.  BibleSync must be transmit-ready, that is, in Personal or Speaker mode.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</sect2>
