<!-- Journals and Prayer Lists -->

		<para>
		<application>Xiphos</application> supports
		user-created and -editable modules to contain general
		content.  Initially conceived as simple prayer lists,
		they have expanded to include daily journals and
		topic-outline content.  The user can maintain prayer
		lists, or prepare sermons, or write any structured
		content desired.
		</para>

		<para>
		To enable prayer list and journal support, see the
		Preferences dialog as previously described.  There, in
                <menuchoice><guisubmenu>General</guisubmenu><guimenuitem>
		Options</guimenuitem></menuchoice>, check the
		item labeled
		<guimenuitem>Enable Prayer Lists</guimenuitem>.
		You will see a new item appear at the bottom of the
		sidebar's module list for "Prayer Lists/Journals".
		</para>

		<para>
		Right-click on this entry, and you will be offered a
		context menu to create new modules.  All the offered
		options are of the same type, but what is offered is a
		variety of templates from which to work.  There are 6
		templates at this time.
		</para>

		<figure>
    		<title>Creating a journal or prayer list</title>
     		<screenshot> 
		  <mediaobject> 
		    <imageobject><imagedata
			fileref="figures/journal.png" format="PNG" />
		    </imageobject>
		    <textobject> 
		      <phrase>New journal or prayer list</phrase> 
		    </textobject> 
		  </mediaobject> 
	        </screenshot>
	        </figure>

		<para>
		Their structure is the same, but the offered templates
		provide a variety of hints regarding ways to organize
		content.  <guimenuitem>Simple</guimenuitem> is
		trivial, and can be considered a mental Post-It
		note.  <guimenuitem>Subject</guimenuitem> is useful as
		a more organized version.
		<guimenuitem>Monthly</guimenuitem> provides a
		per-month structure in which to track needed content.
		<guimenuitem>Daily Journal</guimenuitem> is a full
		365-day calendar in which to track a personal journal
		or ongoing prayer needs.
		<guimenuitem>Outlined Topic</guimenuitem> is a full,
		expandable outline suitable for topics and subtopics.
		<guimenuitem>Book/Chapter</guimenuitem> is a book and
		chapter outline from Genesis through Revelation.
		</para>

		<para>
		Journals and prayer lists have the structure of a
		general book: If simply selected for display from the
		module list, they will appear in the usual subwindow
		for general books.
		</para>

		<para>
		Editing a journal or prayer list is done by
		right-clicking the module name to get its context
		menu, whose middle item is <guimenuitem>Open in
		Editor</guimenuitem>.  The sections and subsections
		will be listed in the left margin.  Click one, and the
		editor navigates to that section.  The context menu on
		right-click of section keys provides for adding,
		deleting, and editing the names of sections and
		subsections.
		</para>

		<para>
		If the general book subwindow is currently displaying
		the journal or prayer list being edited, it will
		synchronize with new content when
		<guimenuitem>Save</guimenuitem> is used.
		</para>

		<para>
		As mentioned, these user-edited modules are in effect
		general books.  This means they can be viewed in any
		Sword Project application.  Thus, you can use these
		modules immediately in
		<application>BibleTime</application>, for example; or
		from the Module Manager's
		<guimenuitem>Maintenance</guimenuitem> page, you can
		archive a zip file to copy to a Windows system where
		you can then install the zip content as a module for
		the Windows user interface.  Few other Sword Project
		applications provide for editing these modules,
		however, meaning that they will appear in such other
		applications as just ordinary general books.
		</para>

		<para>
		In the future, it is planned that a module sharing
		facility will become available, by which user-edited
		modules such as these can be uploaded to become
		available to a wide audience.  The current install
		repository facility will be expanded to provide upload
		as well as the existing download capability in order
		to support this.  Thus, users will be able to share
		their sermons, Bible studies, and other
		personally-authored content with other Sword
		application users.
		</para>
