<!-- Preferences -->


<!-- Introduction -->
	<sect2 id="preferences-introduction">
  		<title>Introduction To Preferences</title>
		<figure>
			<title>The Preference Dialog</title>
	        	<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata
		fileref="figures/preferences.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/preferences.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>The Preferences Dialog</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
                        </screenshot>
                </figure>
               </sect2>
	
<!-- General Settings -->
	<sect2 id="general-settings">
		<title>General Settings</title>
		<sect3 id="tab-pane2">
			<title>Locale, General Preferences and StudyPad directory</title>
		<figure>
			<title>Locale, General Preferences and StudyPad directory</title>
	        	<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata
		fileref="figures/preferences_general-misc.png" format="PNG" />
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/preferences_general-misc.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>General Preferences and StudyPad directory</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
                        </screenshot>

                </figure>
		<para>
                If you wish <application>Xiphos</application> to display its interface in a language other than the default, you may select
                one here.  A restart will be required, so that the locale can be initialized.
		</para>
		<para>
                If you enable <guilabel>Default Dictionary</guilabel>, then that named dictionary (see <guimenuitem>Special</guimenuitem>
                below) module will always be used when double-clicking a word anywhere in <application>Xiphos</application>.
		</para>
		<para>
		Certain dictionary-style modules are <guilabel>Daily Devotionals</guilabel> whose keys are numerically in the form "Month.Day".  If you have
		such a module installed and it has been selected as your preferred devotional, then you can ask that <application>Xiphos</application>
		display today's selection during startup.
		</para>
		<para>
		If you enable <guilabel>Resize images</guilabel>, <application>Xiphos</application> will automatically resize image
		content in commentaries, general books, and dictionaries so as to fit the subwindow which contains them.
		</para>
		<para>
		<guilabel>Highlight current verse</guilabel>, if enabled, will cause <application>Xiphos</application> to substitute
		mere current verse colorization with a high-contrast alternate color scheme on the current verse.  The colors used may be
		chosen from the color selector pane (see below).
		</para>
		<para>
                <guilabel>Highlight user annotations</guilabel> uses inverted highlight color choices when marking user-annotated
                verses.
		</para>
		<para>
                By default, <guilabel>Cross-references</guilabel> go into the Previewer.  Selecting this checkbox puts them into the verse
                list instead.
		</para>
		<para>
                Verse number display can be offset in several ways provided by the checkboxes.
		</para>
                </sect3>
	</sect2>
	
<!-- General Settings -->
	<sect2 id="biblesync">
		<title>BibleSync Settings</title>
		<sect3 id="tab-bsp">
			<title>Controls for BibleSync</title>
		<figure>
			<title>Controls for BibleSync</title>
	        	<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata
		fileref="figures/preferences_general-biblesync.png" format="PNG" />
	    </imageobject>
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>BibleSync Settings</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
                        </screenshot>

                </figure>
		<para>
		BibleSync is a shared navigation protocol using LAN multicast.  It is useful for a single person when running Bible programs on
		multiple machines or devices, all of which you wish to navigate through the Bible together, or for a group working closely together,
		such as translators.  Also, it has a "lecture" mode, where a speaker's Bible program induces the audience's programs to follow along.
		The difference in the modes regards who transmits and who receives navigation.  In Personal mode, BibleSync navigation is both
		transmitted and received; as Speaker, it transmits only; as Audience, it receives only.
		</para>
		<para>
		To enable BibleSync, select a mode from the radio buttons.  Also, choose whether to accept navigation directly, so that Xiphos moves
		immediately to a specified verse, or whether incoming navigation is instead sent to the verse list, where you can decide whether to
		follow.
		</para>
		<para>
		If you use a firewall, you must punch a hole in it for UDP port 22272.
		</para>
		<para>
		If you run more than one BibleSync-compatible program on your computer and do not wish your activity among them to be shared on the
		local net, you can use Personal mode combined with the Private checkbox.  This will tell <application>Xiphos</application> not to
		broadcast outside your system.
		</para>
		<para>
		You can send a verse list from the sidebar search or Advanced Search window via BibleSync; see the context (right-click) menu.  A
		particularly good use case for this is when using a simpler Bible program, such as on a mobile device, with another such as
		<application>Xiphos</application> that has significant search capability: Do searches in <application>Xiphos</application> and send
		the resulting verse list to the mobile device.  Be aware that size limitations on the protocol are small, and though a search may
		generate hundreds of results in the verse list, at most a few dozen will pass in the protocol to the receivers.  For
		<application>Xiphos</application>, receipt of multi-references always induces indirect verse list navigation.
		</para>
		<para>
		<application>Xiphos</application> is the first Bible program with a BibleSync implementation; as such, its utility may be limited for
		now.  But a number of other programs' authors and support organizations have indicated their intention to support BibleSync as well,
		including Laridian, theWord, BibleAnalyzer, and Accordance, as well as other Sword Project applications.
		</para>
                </sect3>
	</sect2>
	
<!-- Fonts And Colors -->
	<sect2 id="fonts-and-colors">
		<title>Fonts And Colors</title>
		<sect3 id="font-color">
			<title>Setting Font Colors</title>
			<figure>
			<title>Font Colour Settings</title>
	        	<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata
		fileref="figures/preferences_fonts-color.png" format="PNG" />
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/image.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>Font Colour Settings</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
                        </screenshot>

                </figure>
		<para>
		The <guibutton>Invert color pairs</guibutton> buttons are provided to make it easy, for example, to move the main window
		into "night mode," with white text on black background.
		</para>

                </sect3>
		
		<sect3 id="font-misc">
			<title>Miscellaneous Font Settings</title>
			<figure>
			<title>Miscellaneous Font Settings</title>
	        	<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata
		fileref="figures/preferences_fonts-misc.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/preferences_fonts-misc.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>Miscellaneous Font Settings</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
                        </screenshot>
                </figure>

		<para>
		In individual modules' display, the right-click menu's <guimenuitem>Module Options</guimenuitem> selector provides font name
		and size selection.
		</para>

		<para>
		The base font size is the size initially chosen for all modules displayed by <application>Xiphos</application>.  The
		verse number and individual modules' font size choices are relative to the base font size.
		</para>

		<para>
                The font name and size used for display is chosen from this order:
		</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>
                                The selection made via the context menu for the specific module, under <guimenuitem>Module
                                Options</guimenuitem>.
                                </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>
                                The per-language selection made under Preferences, here.
                                </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>
                                The module's own default selection, in its configuration file.
                                </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>
                                The application default.
                                </para>
                        </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>

		</sect3>
	</sect2>
	
<!-- Module Settings -->
	<sect2 id="module-settings">
		<title>Module Settings</title>
		<figure>
			<title>Parallel Preferences</title>
	        	<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata
		fileref="figures/preferences_modules-parallel.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/preferences_modules-parallel.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>Parallel Preferences</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
                        </screenshot>

                </figure>
                <figure>
			<title>Various preferences Modules </title>
	        	<screenshot> 
	  <mediaobject> 
	    <imageobject><imagedata
		fileref="figures/preferences_modules-misc.png" format="PNG" /> 
	    </imageobject>
	    <!-- EPS versions of the figures are not required at the moment. -->
            <!-- 
		    <imageobject>
      		<imagedata fileref="figures/preferences_modules-misc.eps" format="EPS"/>
    		    </imageobject>
	    -->
	    <textobject> 
	      <phrase>Various Preferences Modules</phrase> 
	    </textobject> 
	  </mediaobject> 
	
                        </screenshot>

                </figure>
	</sect2>

