<!-- ============= Introduction  ============-->

<para>We welcome new translations, but please be aware that translations are not
  just one time jobs. They have to be maintained in order to be useful. For a
  time committment, translating the interface for the first time will take
  approximately a weekend. After that, it takes approximately two hours every
  three months to keep it updated. Installer translations are much shorter, and
  manual translations are more work than the interface.
</para>

<sect2 id="intro-skills-needed">
  <title>Skills Needed</title>
  <para>Translating the interface at minimum simply requires the knowledge of
    the language you are working on plus English. In addition, you will need to
    learn to use a small simple program to edit the translation. More advanced
    users are encouraged to use svn and other tools to keep up with the
    translation work.
  </para>
</sect2>

<sect2 id="intro-translatable-items">
  <title>Translatable Items</title>
  <para>There are 4 different things that need translation</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Interface: by interface, we mean &app; itself. This includes the
	menus and all messages that might appear to the user. See 
	<link linkend='xiphospo' endterm="xiphospo.title">Translating 
           from a PO file</link>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>User Manual: this is the manual or help file that explains how to
	use &app; . This includes translating all of the text as well as
	creating screenshots for various items. See <link linkend='manual' 
        endterm="manual.title">Translating the Manual</link>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Windows Installer: translate the strings used in the Windows
	installer. This is a very small task, requiring just a text editor.
	See <link linkend='installer' endterm="installer.title">Translating
	  the Installer</link>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para> &app; Website: translate a few pages of the website into another
	language. The process is very similar to translating the interface. 
	See <link linkend='website' endterm="website.title">Translating the Website</link>.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</sect2>
