<!-- ============= Translating Xiphos from a PO  ============-->

<para>At the most basic level, all you need to do to create a new translation is edit a "po" file in a text editor or a translation editor. If you are unable to create this file yourself (described in the next section), someone from the &app; team will assist you in creating the po file for you to edit.</para>

<sect2 id="po-file-structure">
  <title>PO File Structure</title>
  <para>PO files are essentially text files with an entry for each string which requires translation.</para>
  <para>Each entry consists of three or four parts:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      #: ../xiphos.desktop.in.in.h:1
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      msgid "Xiphos Bible Guide"
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      msgstr "زیفوس-نرم·افزار·مطالعه·کتابمقدس"
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

    <para>A comment line pointing towards the exact origin of the particular string within the source code</para>
    <para>A msgid line which quotes the original string</para>
    <para>A msgstr line which contains the relevant translation.</para>
    <para>
      A translation which is doubtful can carry a second comment line, declaring it as "fuzzy":
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	#: ../ui/prefs.glade.h:21
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	#, fuzzy
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	msgid "Base text size"
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	msgstr "سایز قلم بنیادی"  
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
</sect2>

<sect2 id="po-do-translation">
 <title>Editing the PO</title> 
 <para>To edit the po, simply open it in a text editor or one of the translation editors. Then, edit the msgstr line for all of the untranslated terms to the relevant term in your target language. It is helpful to have Xiphos running while doing this so you can see where the terms are being used.
  </para>
</sect2>

<sect2 id="po-programs">
  <title>Translation Editors</title>
  <para>Besides a simple text editor, there are two programs that can make translation easier to do.</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      gtranslator: This program is available for linux (and other *nixes) only.
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      poedit: This program is available on Windows and linux.
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</sect2>
